

As a software developer, my heart definitely belongs to JavaScript. This language kept me aspiring every day, for more than 4 years.

In general, I like to spend my free time learning and trying out whatever seems reasonable. I would even say, that learning is my passion. I like to watch tutorials, do small home projects, create responsive web apps and even I used to build gadgets with Arduino boards. When I look back in time, I see a pattern behind me. I prefer simple and clean solutions and the usefulness of the product is always my number one priority.

Among my personality traits, there is one, that I consider very special. It is a passion, or let me say some ability to ignite myself for a good idea. It is that one which truly pushes me forward. I believe that everything is learnable and possible, but it will never be awesome without one's spark.

I consider myself as a very happy and active person. I love life, people, and especially my family and I absolutely admire honesty.

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Full name Jozef LackoCurrent address Vienna, Austria

• **Age** 29

Nationality Slovak, EUMarital status Engaged

Email jlacko27@gmail.comPhone (+421) 902 092 669

LinkedIn linkedin.com/in/jozeflacko

WORK EXPERIENCE

May 2016 - Present

Java / Javascript Software Developer Workflow EDV GmbH, Vienna, Austria

I work as a developer on an enterprise web application, focusing mostly on time management, travel management, and personnel management. My main responsibilities are implementing responsive skin and improving the user experience of the app by transferring back-event driven events into the scripts run by the browsers. I write reusable components, JavaScript modules, java rest services and page specific CSS. I work in a small team of 6 people and we follow Scrum process. My work also includes creating new actions and workflows in the application, supporting trainees with JavaScript development, taking care of morning builds, fixing broken unit tests, and making regular app releases.

Technologies: JavaScript, Ajax, Jquery library, HTML, CSS, XSLT, Java, Maven, Spring framework, JUnit Test Framework, Eclipse IDE, SVN, Vue, Git, TypeScript

June 2015 - April 2016

Software Developer Internship Workflow EDV GmbH, Vienna, Austria

As a trainee, I was a full-valued team member developing a Java enterprise web application. After a short introduction period, I was implementing new Java services, jobs, JUnit tests, and new actions. Later my tasks were changed to be more concentrated on JavaScript development. I focused on different reusable functionalities for application menu, responsive tables, trees, forms, dialogs and etc.

Technologies: JavaScript, Ajax, Jquery, HTML, CSS, XSLT, Java, Maven, Spring framework, JUnit Test Framework, Eclipse IDE

September 2014 - October 2014

Software Developer Internship University of Tokyo, Japan

With the help of IAESTE (International Association for the Exchange of Students for Technical Experience), I was successfully accepted for a 10 weeks internship at University of Tokyo, Japan. I did a research aimed to effectiveness of parallel computation of multiplication sparse matrices for which I was programming mainly in Fortran programming language. I would like to mention, that this internship was my first experience abroad and a great opportunity to experience other cultures, for which I am absolutely thankful.

Technologies: C. Fortran 77, Eclipse IDE

April 2015 - May 2015 July 2014 - November 2014

ASP.NET Developer

Technical University of Kosice, Slovakia

During my university studies, I was working on 3rd party projects at my Alma mater. Our client was one of the subsidiaries of the United States Steel Corporation placed in Slovakia. In a team of 7 people, we implemented 2 ASP.Net Razor enterprise web applications responsible for managing production of an iron ore.

We were fully responsible for communication with the client, including to inform them of our work progress by engaging them in weekly meetings. My main responsibility in this project was front-end development.

Both projects were successfully finished and given to the client on time.

Technologies: JavaScript, Ajax, Jquery library, HTML, CSS, C#, ASP.NET Razor markup language, Visual Studio IDE

January 2014 - March 2014

Computer systems tester

Icos, a.s., Kosice, Slovakia

As a tester, I was participating on a final development stage of a national project about electronic documents for tax returns lasting 3 months. My main responsibilities were to test web tax forms, validate JavaScript calculations, XML documents and document all found issues. I was collaborating with a team of 10 people.

Technologies: JavaScript, XML

EDUCATION

September 2013 - May 2015

Master of Business Informatics

Department of Cybernetics and Artificial Intelligence Faculty of Electrical Engineering and Informatics Technical University of Kosice, Slovakia

My engineer degree study programme was focused on the acquirement of theoretical and practical knowledge in the field of design and development business enterprise systems and on database systems analysis.

Master Thesis: "Implementation of a software system for experimental analysis of methods for aggregation of opinions using Adaboost"

September 2010 - June 2013

Bachelor of Business Informatics

Department of Cybernetics and Artificial Intelligence Faculty of Electrical Engineering and Informatics Technical University of Kosice, Slovakia

My bachelor degree study programme was focused on the acquirement of knowledge in the field of computer network management, data analysis, business economy, design of business enterprise systems and programming.

SKILLS & PROFICIENCY

Hard skills

- JavaScript, React, JQuery, Ajax, Angular, Typescript, Webpack, Node.js, Webpack, Vue
- Java, Maven, Spring framework, JUnit, SQL and NoSQL databases, HTML, XML, XSL, UML, CSS, Object oriented programming paradigm, Eclipse IDE

Soft skills

- Team player
- Communicative
- Self learning
- Responsible
- Honest
- Assertive

LANGUAGES

- Slovak Native
- English Advanced
- Czech Advanced
- Hungarian Advanced
- German Intermediate
- Russian Beginner